Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
In the last two steps, we implemented a simple problem in a structured approach and the functional approach
在上两步中，我们用结构化方法和功能化方法实现了一个简单的问题
and you might be thinking now that the functional approach is much more complex than this structured
你现在可能会想，功能化方法要比结构化方法复杂得多
approach.
方法复杂得多。
And that's true with the implementation that we have right now.
而我们现在的实现也是如此。
Let's see what we can do to simplify the implementation that we have.
让我们看看我们能做些什么来简化我们的实现。
So, let's first remove all this stuff that we have in here.
所以，让我们先把这里的所有东西都删除。
So, let's actually remove the earlier code that we have inside the functional method.
所以，让我们实际上删除我们在功能方法中的早期代码。
I'm using Ctrl D or command D to remove a line and now let's see the need for this specific print method.
我使用Ctrl D或命令D来删除一行，现在让我们看看这个特定的打印方法的必要性。
What we are doing in here is, we would want to call FP Functional colon colon print.
我们在这里要做的是，我们要调用FP Functional colon colon print。
We would want to call a static method in this specific class.
我们想在这个特定的类中调用一个静态方法。
And what happens is, for each element in this stream, this static method is called with that element.
发生的情况是，对于这个流中的每个元素，这个静态方法都会被调用。
So, this stream contains a list of numbers.
所以，这个流包含一个数字列表。
So, first 12 is sent to this method,
所以，第一个12被送到这个方法、
next nine is sent to this method,
下一个9被送到这个方法、
next 13 is sent to this method and we saw everything is printed out to the console.
下一个13被送到这个方法，我们看到所有的东西都被打印到了控制台。
That's cool.
这很酷。
Now, instead of doing this, you can actually replace this piece of code by directly specifying System.out
现在，你可以不这样做，而是直接在这里指定System.out
in here.
来代替这段代码。
So, System.out and what is this static method? println.
那么，System.out和这个静态方法是什么？ println。
So, System.out contains a static method called println and that's a easier way of doing it. Instead
所以，System.out包含一个叫println的静态方法，这是个更简单的方法。这是一个更简单的方法，而不是
of creating a new method called print,
而不是创建一个叫 print 的新方法、
what we can do is, directly call System.out::println.
我们可以做的是，直接调用System.out::println。
And now, this method is no longer needed.
现在，这个方法已经不再需要了。
So, let's comment it out.
所以，让我们把它注释掉。
Now, you can see that this piece of code is a little more simpler than the structured approach.
现在，你可以看到，这段代码比结构化的方法要简单一些。
Why do I call it simpler?
为什么我说它更简单呢？
Because in this Structured approach, we had to focus on how to loop the numbers and then print them. In
因为在这个结构化方法中，我们不得不把重点放在如何循环数字，然后打印它们。而在
the Functional approach,
功能性方法中、
on the other hand, we get a list of elements and we define what to do with each one of them.
另一方面，我们得到一个元素的列表，并定义对每个元素做什么。
So, all that we needed to do is to say for each element in this stream, do this. Now,
因此，我们所需要做的就是对这个流中的每个元素说，做这个。现在、
let's try and make the example that we have little bit more complex.
让我们试着让我们的例子更复杂一些。
What I want to do is, I would want to go to the FP Structured class and what I would want to do is to
我想做的是，我想转到FP结构化类，我想做的是
print only the even numbers.
只打印偶数。
I don't want to print all the numbers in the list but I only want to print the even numbers in the list.
我不想打印列表中的所有数字，但我只想打印列表中的偶数。
So, instead of saying print all numbers in the list,
所以，与其说是打印列表中的所有数字，不如说是打印偶数、
I only want to say print even numbers in the list structured.
我只想说打印列表结构中的偶数。
How do we change this code to print even numbers in the list?
我们如何改变这段代码来打印列表中的偶数？
Think about it.
想一想吧。
Typically, what we do is, we would add the logic in here. So, we'll say, if this is even, only then print
通常情况下，我们所做的是，我们会在这里添加逻辑。所以，我们会说，如果这个是偶数，就打印
the number out, right?
的数字，对吗？
So, let's do that.
所以，让我们这样做吧。
So, if even,
那么，如果是偶数、
how can I check that the number is even? If(number), we can divide
我怎样才能检查这个数字是偶数呢？如果(数)，我们可以除以
by two. So number%2==0.
除以2。所以number%2==0。
So, we are dividing by two and checking the remainder. So, number%2 divides the number by two and checks
所以，我们要除以2并检查余数。所以，number%2除以2并检查
the remainder.
余数。
If it's zero,  then what do we want to do? Yes, we would want to print the number out.
如果是零，那么我们要做什么？是的，我们想把这个数字打印出来。
So, let's format this out.
所以，让我们把这个格式化出来。
And now, if I call this, so printEvenNumbersInListStructured, I can copy and paste this in but then
现在，如果我调用这个，那么printEvenNumbersInListStructured，我可以复制并粘贴这个，但这样的话
I would be repeating the list.
我将会重复这个列表。
I don't really want to do that.
我真的不想这样做。
So, what we'll do is, let's extract this list to a local variable. So, right-click, List factor, extract to
所以，我们要做的是，让我们把这个列表提取到一个局部变量。所以，右键单击，列表因子，提取到
a local variable and local variable that I would want to create is numbers and over here, what we want
我想创建的局部变量是数字，在这里，我们要做的是
to do is, we would want to print all the even numbers in the list. Right.
要做的是，我们要打印列表中的所有偶数。对。
So, that's basically what we want to do.
所以，这基本上就是我们想要做的事情。
So we are using the Structured approach and let's run as Java Application. What would happen? Cool. Only the even
所以我们使用结构化方法，让我们作为Java应用程序运行。会发生什么？很酷。只有偶数
numbers are getting printed.
数字被打印出来。
Now how do we do the same thing in a Functional approach?
现在，我们如何在Functional方法中做同样的事情？
How do I do that in a FP01functional class? Let's see how to do that right now.
如何在FP01functional类中做到这一点？我们现在就来看看如何做到这一点。
So, I'll copy the existing method. As usual,
所以，我将复制现有的方法。像往常一样、
I'll call this printEvenNumbersInListFunctional and over here,
我把这个方法叫做printEvenNumbersInListFunctional，然后在这里、
what we want to do is, we'd want to only look at the numbers which are even. So how do I add additional logic
我们想做的是，我们想只看偶数的数字。那么我如何在这里添加额外的逻辑
in here. I can add a Filter in here. I'll say, only allow even numbers.
在这里。我可以在这里添加一个过滤器。我会说，只允许偶数。
How can I add a Filter? The way I can do that is by saying .filter.
我怎样才能添加一个过滤器呢？我可以通过说.filter来做到这一点。
Now, how do I decide if something is even? Let's create a static method for it, for now. I'll call this private
现在，我如何决定一个东西是否是偶数？让我们为它创建一个静态方法，现在。我把这个方法称为私有
static, this return whether it's even or not. So I'll say boolean, private static boolean isEven
static，这个方法返回它是否是偶数。所以我会说布尔值，私有静态布尔值isEven
and let's pass the number to it.
让我们把数字传给它。
So, int number and this would return.
所以，int number，这个会返回。
What does it return?
它的返回值是什么？
number%2
is equal to, is equal to zero.
等于，等于零。
This is simple logic. Right?
这就是简单的逻辑。对吗？
All that it does is, it divides the number by two, checks the remainder, and if the remainder is zero, it returns a
它所做的就是，将数字除以2，检查余数，如果余数为零，它就返回一个
'true' back.
'真'返回。
Otherwise it returns a 'false' back.
否则它返回一个 "假"。
What do you want to do is, we would want to call this method on each of these numbers.
你想做的是，我们想在这些数字中的每一个上调用这个方法。
And only if it is true, we'd want to print the number. So you'd want to do a forEach,
只有当它为真时，我们才想打印这个数字。所以你想做一个forEach、
only for the numbers
只对那些
where isEven is returning true.
其中isEven返回true。
How do we do that in the Functional approach?
我们如何在函数式方法中做到这一点呢？
The way we can do that is by creating a filter.
我们可以通过创建一个过滤器来做到这一点。
So I said .filter and over here, I can say isEven.
所以我说.filter，在这里，我可以说isEven。
And because this is a static method, the way we can define that is by using a method reference FP01
因为这是一个静态方法，我们可以通过使用方法引用FP01来定义它。
Functional colon
功能性冒号
colon isEven. The important thing in the method reference is that we are not really calling it, we are
冒号isEven。方法引用的重要之处在于，我们并没有真正调用它，我们并没有
not really calling it. We are just saying, okay, this is a method to be called.
不是真正的调用。我们只是说，好吧，这是一个要被调用的方法。
We are declaring that this is a method to be called on each of the numbers and if it returns true back,
我们声明这是一个在每个数字上被调用的方法，如果它返回真值、
only then go to the next line of code.
然后再转到下一行代码。
So, let's move this comment out, down to this side and let's now execute this. Let's quickly create a local
所以，让我们把这个注释移出来，移到这一边，现在我们来执行这个。让我们迅速为这个列表创建一个本地
variable for this list as well, numbers. And what we want to do is, copy this and we would want to print
变量，也就是数字。我们要做的是，复制这个，我们要打印出
even numbers in the list.
列表中的偶数。
Let's comment this out.
让我们把这个注释出来。
Let's quickly run this and see what would happen.
让我们快速运行这个，看看会发生什么。
Do we get only even numbers?
我们是否只得到偶数？
Yup.
是的。
That's cool.
这很好。
Now, we saw that we were able to print all the even numbers in the list.
现在，我们看到我们能够打印列表中所有的偶数。
Once again, you can see the fact that once we have a stream of numbers, all that we needed to do was add
再一次，你可以看到这样一个事实：一旦我们有了一个数字流，我们所需要做的就是添加
a check.
一个校验。
So, for each number, do this check. If that check is true, then you can actually go ahead and print the
所以，对于每个数字，做这个检查。如果这个检查是真的，那么你就可以继续打印这个
number out.
数字了。
Now, again you might be thinking that this method is a little bit more complex than this structured approach
现在，你可能又在想，这个方法比这个结构化的方法要复杂一些
because we needed to use a method called isEven.
因为我们需要使用一个叫做isEven的方法。
How would it be, if I can actually directly define the entire
如果我真的可以直接定义整个
isEven method in here.
isEven方法。
Instead of actually creating a separate method, having a return value, having the parameters defined,
而不是实际创建一个单独的方法，有一个返回值，有定义的参数、
having the body, having the return and all that, can we do it in a simpler way and directly define the
有主体，有返回等等，我们能不能用一种更简单的方式，直接在这里定义这个
method in here.
方法。
Let's look at that in the subsequent step. Until then,
让我们在接下来的步骤中看看这个问题。在那之前、
bye, bye.
拜拜，拜拜。